sysprogs.org 2019-12-02

# Sysprogs - Privacy Policy

Last revised: May 23, 2018

### Who we are

Sysprogs OÜ, controls the personal data you submit to us and is responsible for your personal data under applicable data protection law.  
We can be contacted via the [contact form](https://sysprogs.com/contact/) on our website.

### What we collect

We may collect information about the use of this website. We use this information to improve our website and services. This information is not personally linked to you.

We may also collect your contact data and payment data. This information is used to handle your orders and provide support.

We may collect the following personal information when you place an order with us:

  * Full name.
  * Company name and VAT ID if applicable.
  * Address.
  * Country.
  * Email address.
  * Phone number and fax number.
  * IP address.
  * Payment processing information.

This information is collected by [ 2Checkout](http://www.2checkout.com/) (our online payment processor) in order to process and fullfill your order and is further processed by us in order to validate the orders. We do not have access to credit card numbers, or any sensitive payment-related information, as it is handled directly by our payment processor.

For each Sysprogs license we store the following information:

  * Contact name.
  * Company name if applicable.
  * Contact email address.
  * Purchase date.
  * The purchased product, edition and the amount of seats purchased.
  * Unique IDs of seats on which the license has been activated, together with the activation dates.

This information is used to verify the status of your license, technical support, and issue automatic renewal/upgrade quotes. 

We collect the following information when you contact us:

  * Contact information such as name and email address
  * Support correspondence, including any attachments (e.g. proof of academic status)

This information is used to provide answers to your inquiries.

### How we handle your information

All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. We implement appropriate measures to protect your personal data against unauthorized or unlawful access.

### Sharing information

We may disclose your personal information to appropriate third parties. Such third parties include the order and payment processing companies we use and to comply with legal requirements. We will not sell or rent your personal information to third parties. Your personal information may be processed, stored or transferred outside your country of residence and beyond the European Union or the European Economic Area. However, personal information will continue to be protected in accordance with this privacy policy and EU standard contractual clauses.

### How will the personal information be used

We may process personal information for the following purposes: for providing services to you, providing support, meeting our legal obligations (e.g. bookkeeping, accounting), managing our IT systems, ensuring the security of our systems and improving our services.

### How long will we store the personal information

We will retain your personal information for as long as it required to fulfill the purposes as outlined in this privacy policy. Personal information for order processing is retained in compliance with the bookkeeping rules in your country and the EU.

### What are your rights

You have the right to object to the processing of your personal information in certain situations e.g. for marketing purposes at any time.  
Depending on where you live, you may have additional privacy rights.  
For example under EU laws you have the following additional rights:

  * to access information we hold about you;
  * to request that we delete your personal information from our system unless legally required;
  * to ask us to rectify/correct your personal information if appropriate;
  * to ask us to restrict processing of your personal information;
  * to transmit your personal information to another entity;
  * to lodge a complaint with a data protection authority.

You can exercise these rights by filing a GDPR request via our [support form](https://sysprogs.com/support/?topic=gdpr) or via the email addresses specified on our [ contact page](https://sysprogs.com/contact/).

### Security

We are commited to keeping your information secure. We have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

### Links to other websites

This website may contain links to other websites. We have no control over the content and privacy policies of other websites. You are responsible for checking the privacy policy on these websites.

### Google Analytics

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (â€œGoogleâ€). Google Analytics uses â€œcookiesâ€, which are text files placed on your computer, to help the website analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States.

In case IP-anonymisation is activated on this website, your IP address will be truncated within the area of Member States of the European Union or other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases the whole IP address will be first transfered to a Google server in the USA and truncated there. The IP-anonymisation is active on this website.

Google will use this information on behalf of the operator of this website for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing them other services relating to website activity and internet usage.

The IP-address, that your Browser conveys within the scope of Google Analytics, will not be associated with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. You can also opt-out from being tracked by Google Analytics with effect for the future by downloading and installing Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Addon for your current web browser: <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>.

### Google Adsense

This website uses Google Adsense, a web advertisement service provided by Google, Inc. ("Google"), to serve ads on portions of the website. Google Adsense uses cookies to serve ads based on your prior visits to the website. Google's use of the DoubleClick cookie enables it and its partners to serve ads based on your visits to our website and/or other sites on the Internet.

You can opt out of the use of the DoubleClick cookie for interest-based advertising by visiting [Ads Settings](http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/).

Other third-party vendors and ad networks may use cookies to serve ads on our website.

You can opt out of some third-party vendor's use of cookies for interest-based advertising by visiting [aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/).

You can read more about Google's use of data from their [partner site privacy policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/partners/).

For users within the EEA, this website will show only non-personalized ads.

### Changes to this policy

We may revise this policy from time to time. If we make material changes, then we change the â€žlast revisedâ€œ date above. You should check periodically for changes.
